Hello, and welcome to Lesson 32 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
大家好，这里是 Wolfram U的微积分入门，第31课
The topic for this lesson is approximate integration.
本次课程的主题是 积分近似
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
让我们从本课的简要概述开始
So far, you’ve been using integration to calculate
到目前为止 你一直在使用积分来算
the area under curves, et cetera, and the point is
曲线下的面积 等等 要点是
if you can compute an integral, then you can work out the area.
能算出积分 就能算出面积
For example, if you can work out the integral of x^2,
例如 如果你能计算 x^2 的积分
which is of course x^3/3, then you can work out
当然答案是 x^3/3 然后你就能算出
the area under the curve for y = x^2 between,
曲线 y = x^2 下区域间的面积
let’s say, 2 and 5 in two ways:
假设有 2 和 5 现在有两种方法
either you can actually plug in the upper and lower limits 5 and 2
一个是实际上上限 5 和下限 2代到
in the answer on the earlier step or you can use Integrate,
在上一步的答案中 或者可以使用 Integrate
and you get back just the same result.
都能得到相同的结果
The point is that some functions have no known closed form
关键是某些函数没有已知的闭形式
for their integrals.
对他们的积分而言
Here’s an example: e^e^x^2 does not have an integral.
例如 e^e^x^2  就没有原函数
The question is what do we do in such a case?
问题是这时候我们怎么办
How do you find the area under the curve in such cases?
这是怎么算曲线下方的面积
In this lesson, we’ll go over some ways
这节课 我们将介绍一些方法
to evaluate such integrals numerically or approximately.
计算这些积分 在数值上或是近似的
As a first step, let’s look at so-called left and right approximations.
首先 来看一下所谓的左近似和右近似
When we began integration, we talked about the area of a region
当我们积分时 我们谈到了区域上的面积
as being a kind of Riemann sum, so you have the function value
是一种黎曼和 所以你有函数值
at some sample points times the length of each subinterval,
在某些采样点上的值 乘 每个子区间长度
and then the sample points could be chosen in various ways.
然后可以通过多种方式选择采样点
In the first case over here, if I choose i – 1 over here,
第一种情况下 如果我们这里选择 i – 1
then basically I get the left-end sample points,
然后基本上就得到了 左采样点
so the rectangles have their upper left-hand corners
所以这个矩形的左上角
lying on the curve.
在曲线上
If you have an i over here,
如果你这里选 i
then you get upper-right corners lying on the curve.
那么右上角就在曲线上
Here’s a plot to show all that.
这个图可以说明一切
In this first case, you have the left approximations,
第一种情况下 你有左近似
and in the second case, you have the right approximations.
在第二个例子里 你有右近似
It’s clear in the first case you’re kind of under approximating,
很明显 第一种情况下 你是一种下近似
and in the second case you’re over approximating.
第二种情况下 是一种上近似
Let’s now actually work out the answers using the sum over here,
现在让我们用此处的总和来计算答案
and you get back the answers 1.285 and 1.385.
然后得 1.285 和 1.385
That’s the left sum.
这是左和
That’s the right sum.
这是右和
The actual answer is sandwiched between those two numbers.
实际答案夹在这两个数字之间
It’s 1.3333, which is somewhere between
他是 1.3333 这就是在
the left and the right answers.
左右答案之间
The question is can we do any better?
问题是我们能做的更好吗？
Well, what we could do is to take
我们能做的是
the midpoints of each subinterval as the sample point.
以每个子区间的中点作为采样点
Here’s the midpoint in each case.
这是每个小长条的中点
Then the rectangles have the middle of their tops
然后矩形有其顶部的中间
going through the curve.
都在曲线上
Here’s a plot with our function,
这里画出我们的函数
and you can see over here that things are better
然后你可以看到变得更好了
because you have some extra area over here, for example,
因为这有些额外的区域 比如这儿
and some less area over there, so it looks like this might give you
还有一些缺了的区域补上了 所以看起来能够给你
a better approximation than the earlier method.
更好的近似相比先前的方法
Let’s do that, and you do find that you get a better approximation.
我们这么做 你就能得到一个更好的近似
Another method might be to use the so-called trapezoidal rule.
另一个方法就是所谓的 梯形法
Earlier we spoke about the left and right approximations,
之前我们谈到了左右近似
and that’s the actual integral.
然后这是实际积分
If you work them out, you can get back 1.285, 1.385, 1.3333.
算出来 可得 1.285 1.385 1.3333
But what you could do is to take an average of the right and left
但是还可以取左右的平均值
and compare it with the actual integral,
再和实际积分做比较
and that definitely looks much better.
这看起来肯定好多了
Effectively what you’re doing is you’re taking a trapezoid
实际上 你在做的就是用梯形
in each case with the height of the trapezoid equal to Δx
在每个时候梯形的高等于 Δx
and the two lengths over here being
两个长度在这里
the lengths of the function heights at those points.
这些点处的函数高度的长度
Here’s the answer for that trapezoidal rule,
这是梯形法的答案
and you get back just the same result.
得到的结果是一样的
Now to go a step further, one could actually try and use polynomials,
更进一步 实际上可以尝试使用多项式
and that’s what is called Simpson’s rule.
这就是所谓的辛普森法
With Simpson’s rule, what we’ll do is use parabolas
根据辛普森法 我们要用抛物线
to approximate the area under the curve.
去近似曲线下面积
But that’s a much harder problem,
但这是更难的一个问题
so you get back a slightly more complicated formula.
所以得到一个稍微复杂的公式
You do need to take an even number of points,
你需要取偶数个点
and then basically you take x0, x1, x2 et cetera in triples
基本上就是取 x0 x1 x2 等三个点
to compute the sum for the area.
去计算这个区域的和
That’s a particular combination.
这是一个特别的组合
You have 1, 4, 1 as the combination on your subinterval.
您的子区间上有 1 4 1 作为组合
Here’s the computation with our earlier example
下面是我们前面的示例的计算
and, let’s say, 10 subregions.
比如说 10 个子区域
What you get back is the exact answer.
你得到的就是确切答案
Simpson’s rule is extremely powerful.
辛普森法及其强大
It tries to use parabolae to compute the approximation,
他用抛物线近似计算
and in this simple case, it actually gets to the exact answer.
再简单的情况下 他实际上能得到正解
Now whenever we do any kind of approximation,
现在 每当我们做任何近似
you need to worry about errors.
你需要担心误差
For the midpoint rule, it turns out that if you have
对于中点规则 事实证明 如果你有
an upper-bound K for the second derivative,
上界 K 对于二阶导数而言是存在的
then that’s the error for the length of b – a for the interval
那么这就是长度为 b – a 的区间上的误差
and n rectangles.
关于 n 个矩形
The trapezoidal rule has a very similar formula,
梯形法有一个很像的公式
but in fact the error is exactly twice the midpoint rule error.
但是事实上误差刚好上中点法的两倍
Simpson’s rule is a lot better
辛普森法好多了
because now you look at the fourth derivative,
因为你能看到四阶导数
and you get back an error term over here.
得到这个误差项
Those are the maximum errors
这都是最大误差
for each method that we have spoken about.
对于我们提到的每一个方法而言
The midpoint case and the trapezoidal case,
中点情形和梯形情形
you can work out the errors—they’re quite small—
可以让他们的误差足够小
and compare them with the actual errors,
并且和实际误差相比较
namely, the difference between the actual integrals
即和实际积分的不同
and the midpoint method and the trapezoidal method,
以及中点法和梯形法
and you get back just the same result.
你都能得到相同的结论
The question now is
现在的问题是
why did Simpson’s rule give you no error?
辛普森法的误差呢？
The point is that you have a quadratic polynomial,
关键在于你有一个二次多项式
so its fourth derivative is 0,
所以他的四阶导数是 0
and so there is no error in the Simpson’s method.
那辛普森法就没有误差
Okay. Fortunately in the Wolfram Language,
好 幸运的是在 Wolfram 语言中
we have a wonderful function called NIntegrate
有一个好用的函数叫 NIntegrate
which actually computes numerical integrals very nicely.
他在实际计算数值积分时非常好
For the example in our introduction, e^e^x^2,
例如介绍中的示例 e^e^x^2
you get back a nice answer quite quickly.
很快就能得到一个很好的答案
Here is a plot of that area.
这是面积的图像
In general, NIntegrate uses very highly optimized methods.
通常 NIntegrate 使用更高阶的优化方法
It does not use any particular method, but it might use
它不使用任何特定方法 但是使用
some very general, efficient algorithm to compute the answer.
一些非常通用 高效的算法来计算答案
You do get back the best possible answer,
您确实会得到最好的答案
and I strongly recommend you check your answers with NIntegrate.
我强烈建议使用 NIntegrate 检查答案
But of course you might say oh, I really want to have
但是你当然可以说 哦 我真的很想有
my own function done my way to compute integrals.
我自己的函数 用自己的方式算积分
Well, you can do that.
当然 你可以
You can make your own functions.
你可以自己写函数
We’ll learn that in a later lesson.
我们将在之后的课程中学习
For numerical integration, you can either make up your own functions
对于数值积分 可以自己的函数
or simply call NIntegrate.
或者简单调用 NIntegrate
They are both fine, but you must decide
他们俩都很好 但是你要做决定
how accurate you want your answer to be.
你需要多到的精度
Okay. Finally, one might sometimes only have a table of values.
好的 最后 有时可能只有一张数值表
Here’s an example.
例如
You’re given a table of values for the speed of a particle
有一张粒子的速度表
at 11 instances of time.
在 11 个时间点处
Those are the times and the speeds,
这些是时刻和速度
and you’ve got the trapezoidal rule.
并且有梯形法
Basically what happens over here is you have the left endpoint
基本上这些事就是你有左端点
and the right endpoint of the intervals,
和区间的右端点
and then you have everything else getting counted twice.
然后你把所有的事情都算了两次
For Simpson’s rule, you have the left endpoint, the right endpoint
根据辛普森法 有左端点 右端点
and then everything else getting counted four times.
然后其他所有事情都被计算了四次
That’s the Simpson’s rule answer.
那就是辛普森法的答案
They are pretty close.
他们非常接近
Here’s a plot of the data.
这是数据图
Basically you can compute a numerical approximation
基本上可以计算出数值近似值
given only a table of values.
仅给出一个数值表
After all, all of today’s formulas depend only upon
毕竟 今天所有的公式仅取决于
knowing the values at a certain fixed number of points.
已知的某个固定点数的值
That brings me to the end of this lesson,
本次课到此为止
and the main point is that if you can’t find
要点是 如果找不到
the integral of a function,
函数的原函数
then you certainly can approximate it by various methods.
那么当然可以通过各种方法对其进行近似
There are various techniques available.
有多种可用的技术
You could use left or right approximations.
可以使用左或右近似
You could use the midpoint rule,
可以使用中点法
the trapezoidal rule or Simpson’s rule.
梯形法 或者 辛普森法
You could also use NIntegrate, which is a very powerful function
也可以调用 NIntegrate 这个强大的函数
and will give you the best possible approximation
将会给你最好的近似
that it came up with while finding the integral.
那是我们积分是想要的
Finally, you can use a table of values
最后 可以使用数值表
to compute a numerical approximation.
计算数值近似值
That’s good enough.
够了
In the next lesson, we’ll go over exponential functions.
在下一课中 我们将介绍指数函数
But before doing that, do review today’s topic.
但是在此之前 请先复习一下今天的主题
It’s a very interesting, useful part of calculus
这是微积分中非常有趣且有用的部分
because very often in practice, you cannot find an exact answer.
因为在实践中 经常得不到确切的答案
In that case, a numerical method is the best that you have.
在这种情况下 数值方法是最好的方法
I’ll stop over here. Thank you very much.
本节课到此为止，再见
翻译：兰州大学 周怀尚